Preliminary Guide to the News Service Press Releases and Clippings, 1948-2009 UA.27.01.0005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
News Service Press Releases and Clippings
1948-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. News Service
UA.27.01.0005
121.5 Linear Feet
0.14 Gigabytes
Contains press releases, clipping files, and National Press Exposure Reports created by the Duke University News Service. Major subjects include Duke University News Service, press releases, public relations, clippings, and mass media. Materials range in date from 1948-2009. English.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
No restrictions.
Electronic records in this collection have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room. To request access, please contact Research Services before coming to use these records.
Provenance
Acquired; 1975-2002.
Acquired; 2002; 2002-52.1 to 2002-52.19.
Acquired; 2002; 2002-69.1 to 2002-69.44.
Transferred; 2010 (UA2010-0025)
Historical Note
The mission of the Duke News Service is to inform the public and the university community about research, programs, and events at Duke; to increase public understanding and appreciation of scholarly contributions made by Duke's faculty and the work of its other employees and students; and to provide media relations and consultative services to faculty and administrators. The Duke News Service accomplishes this mission by working closely with local, national, and international news media, including newspapers, radio and television, magazines, wire services and syndicates.
Collection Overview
Contains clippings, news releases files, and National Press Exposure Reports created by the Duke University News Service. Materials range in date from 1948-2009.
Related Material
News Service subject files, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University. News Service Biographical Files, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Clippings (information artifacts); Mass media -- North Carolina -- Durham; Press releases; Public relations; Duke University. News Service
- Clippings, 1948-1963.
  - 1948 January 1-1949 November 2 (Box 1)
  - 1949 November 3 -1951 October 27 (Box 2)
  - 1951 October 27 -1953 June 1 (Box 3)
  - 1953 June 1-1954 December 26 (Box 4)
  - 1954 December 26-1956 December 16 (Box 5)
  - 1956 December 19-1958 May 24 (Box 6)
  - 1958 May 24-1960 January 31 (Box 7)
  - 1960 February 1-1961 October 21 (Box 8)
  - 1961 October 24-1963 January 7 (Box 9)
- Campus News Releases, 1955-1999.
  - 1955 April-1957 May (Box 10)
  - 1957 June-1958 May (Box 11)
  - 1958 June-1959 April (Box 12)
  - 1959 May-1960 March (Box 13)
  - 1960 April-December (Box 14)
  - 1961-1962 April (Box 15)
  - 1962 May-1963 February (Box 16)
  - 1963 March-December (Box 17)
  - 1972 July-1982 December (Box 18)
  - 1983 January-1989 August (Box 19)
  - 1989 September-1992 May (Box 20)
  - 1992 June- 1994 May (Box 21)
  - 1994 June-1995 July (Box 22)
  - 1995 August-1999 (Box 23)
- Electronic Campus News Releases, 1991-2004
  Conditions Governing Access
  Electronic records in this series have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room. To request access, please contact Research Services before coming to use these records.
  Scope and Contents
  Some electronic records in this series may be a duplicate of records in the Campus News Releases series.
  - News Releases, 1991-1993, bulk 1992; 904 document files; approximately 6 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA27010005-SET-0001)
  - News Releases, 1993; 674 document files; approximately 6 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA27010005-SET-0001)
  - News Releases, 1994; 572 document files; approximately 6 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA27010005-SET-0001)
  - News Releases, 1995; 513 document files; approximately 5 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA27010005-SET-0001)
  - News Releases, 1996; 470 document files; approximately 3 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA27010005-SET-0001)
  - News Releases, 1997; 440 document files; approximately 5 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA27010005-SET-0001)
  - News Releases, 1998-1999, bulk 1998; 507 document files; approximately 10 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA27010005-SET-0001)
  - News Releases, 1998-1999, bulk 1999; 443 files including 427 WordPerfect files, 12 .AR files, and 4 .RM files; approximately 44 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA27010005-SET-0001)
  - News Releases, 2000; 607 document files; approximately 9 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA27010005-SET-0001)
  - News Releases, 2000-2001, bulk 2001; 519 document files; approximately 5 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA27010005-SET-0001)
  - News Releases, 2001-2003, bulk 2002; 566 document files; approximately 11 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA27010005-SET-0001)
  - News Releases, 2003; 607 document files; approximately 12 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA27010005-SET-0001)
  - News Releases, 2004; 610 document files; approximately 12 megabytes. (Digital-materials UA27010005-SET-0001)
- Medical Center News Releases, 1972-1999.
  - 1972 July-1989 June (Box 24)
  - 1989 July-1999 March (Box 25)
- National Press Exposure Reports, 1992-2002.
  - 1992 May-2002 April (Box 26)
- Accession A2002-52
  - News releases (Box 27)
    - 1988 April- 1983 April (Box 27)
    - 1983 February-1983 July (Box 27)
    - 1985 December-1986 October (Box 28)
    - "Aegyptopithecus," Dr. Simons, 1980 (Box 28)
    - 1986 November-1987 April (Box 29)
    - 1987 May-1988 March (Box 30)
    - 1983 August-1984 August (Box 31)
    - 1984 September- 1985 July (Box 32)
    - April 1988-May 1988 (Box 33)
    - 1992 December -1993 September (Box 33)
    - 1993 October-1994 November (Box 34)
    - 1985 September-1985 November (Box 35)
    - 1988 June-1988 July (Box 35)
    - 1994 December-1995 March (Box 35)
  - Clippings (Box 36)
    - Herald Sun
      - 1992 April- 1993 September (Box 36)
      - 1996 February-August (Box 36)
      - 1993 October 1-1996 January 31 (Box 37)
    - North Carolina Press Association, 1971-1981 (Box 38)
    - Raleigh News and Observer, 1993 May 31-1993 December 30 (Box 38)
    - Durham Sun; Durham Morning Herald (Box 39)
      - 1986 August 1-1987 October 31 (Box 39)
      - 1987 November 1-1988 October 31 (Box 40)
      - 1988 November 1-1989 December 7 (Box 41)
      - 1989 December 8-1991 March 27 (Box 42)
  - News releases, 1989 May-1990 November (Box 43)
  - Herald Sun, 1992 February 29-1992 March 31 (Box 43)
  - News releases, 1990 December-1991 November (Box 44)
  - News releases, 1992 February-1992 July (Box 44)
  - Raleigh News and Observer, 1993 June-1996 Jan. (Box 45)
  - News releases, 1992 August-1992 September (Box 45)
- Accession A2002-69
  - Daily news clips (Box 46)
    - 1963 (Box 46)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 47)
    - 1965-1966 July (Box 48)
    - 1966 Aug.-1968 Aug. 1968 (Box 49)
    - Sept.- 1970 Apr. 30 1970 (Box 50)
    - May-1971 Oct. 31 (Box 51)
    - 1971 Nov.-1972 (Box 52)
    - 1973- 1974 June (Box 53)
    - 1974 July-1975 Oct. (Box 54)
    - 1975 Nov.-1977 May 7 (Box 55)
    - 1977 May-1978 Mar. (Box 56)
  - Terry Sanford speeches, 1970-1975 (Box 56)
  - File copies of stories for Inauguration of Dr. Douglas Knight, Durham Sun, 1963 Dec. 10 (Box 56)
  - Durham Morning Herald, 1963 Dec. 11 (Box 56)
  - Duke News Service press releases (Box 57)
    - 1964 (Box 57)
    - 1965 (Box 58)
    - 1966 (Box 59)
    - 1967 (Box 60)
    - 1968 (Box 61)
    - 1969 Jan.-1970 March (Box 62)
    - 1970 April-1971 Aug. (Box 63)
    - 1971 Sept.-1972 Dec. (Box 64)
    - 1973 (Box 65)
    - 1974 (Box 66)
    - 1975 (Box 67)
    - 1976 (Box 68)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 69)
    - File copies, 1977 (Box 70)
    - File copies, 1967, 1968, 1970 (Box 71)
    - File copies, 1969 (Box 72)
    - Edit copies, 1976 (Box 72)
  - Terry Sanford clips
    - 1974 Dec.-1975 June (Box 72)
    - 1975 Dec.-1976 Jan.. (Box 72)
    - 1969-1971 (Box 73)
    - 1972 (Box 74)
  - Duke Forest news releases, 1995 (Box 75)
  - Duke News Service press releases
    - 1996 Jan.-1996 July (Box 75)
    - 1997 Jan.-1997 April (Box 75)
    - 1997 May-1998 Feb. (Box 76)
    - 1998 March -1998 Dec. (Box 77)
  - Medical Center files
    - AIDS Research, 1986-Alzheimer's Disease, 1994 (Box 78)
    - Alzheimer's Disease, 1994 (Box 78)
    - Anatomy, 1986-Cancer, 1994 (Box 79)
    - Cardiology, 1986-Dietetics, 1989 (Box 80)
    - Division of Reproductive Endocrinology-Gerontology (Box 81)
    - Health Administration-Kidney, 1994 (Box 82)
    - Malpractice Suits, 1986-Obstetrics and Gynecology, 1994 (Box 83)
    - Occupational Health, 1986-Pediatrics, 1994 (Box 84)
    - Pharmacology, 1985-Radiology, 1994 (Box 85)
    - Replantation Surgery-Teer House, 1990 (Box 86)
    - Transplants-Veterinary Medicine (Box 87)
  - Subject Files
    - Homecoming, 1975-Inauguration of Brodie (Box 87)
    - Institute of the Arts-Latin American Studies (Box 88)
    - Inauguration-Lectures/Hill Lecture (Box 88)
    - Unprocessed (Box 90)
- Accession UA2010-0025 1994-2009, 9 boxes
  - 1994 April-1995 Oct. (Box 91)
  - 1995 Nov.-1996 Nov. (Box 92)
  - 1996 Dec.-1998 May (Box 93)
  - 1998 June-1999 July (Box 94)
  - 1999 Aug.-2000 June (Box 95)
  - 2000 July-Dec. (Box 96)
  - 2001 Jan.-Sept. (Box 96)
  - 2002 Jan.-May (Box 96)
  - 2002 June-2004 Oct. (Box 97)
  - Clippings, 2003-2004 (Box 97)
  - Clippings, 2005 (Box 98)
  - Clippings, 2005 (cont'd)-2009 (Box 99)
- Accession UA2016-0030, 2004-2015
  - News releases (DukeNews or Office of News and Communications), November 2004 - April 2009 (Box 100)
  - News releases (DukeNews or Office of News and Communications), May 2009 – November 2013 (Box 101)
  - News releases (DukeNews or Office of News and Communications), December 2013 -- November 2015 (Box 102)